

sudbasnet.github.io | linkedin.com/in/sudeepbasnet

Address: **5277 W 82nd ST**

Phone:

Bloomington, MN 402-617-1329

Email: **sudbasnet10@gmail.com**

SUMMARY

Dedicated, career-oriented individual with professional experience in Software & Database Development, and scientific research. Graduated with a master's degree in Computer Science. Has worked in Agile methodology and used technology such as Python, C#, TypeScript, R and JavaScript on Windows and Unix platforms.

SKILLS

Programming: Python, C#, Typescript, JavaScript, HTML/CSS, R, SQL, NoSQL

Other Technical: NodeJS, Angular, Vue, GIT and SVN, Data Analysis, Data Visualization, Database Development,

Azure Fundamentals, JIRA, Snowflake DW, MicroStrategy, Markdown Documentation

EXPERIENCE

Technical Consultant -Software Development & Data Warehousing | Oct 2019 - Current

Logic Information Systems, Bloomington, MN

Software Developer | May 2020 - Current

• Developing omni-channel e-commerce solutions with C#, TypeScript, and HTML/CSS in .NET and .NET Core.

Data Warehouse and BI Developer | Oct 2019 - Feb 2020

- Debugged and resolved issues in reporting dashboards, using MicroStrategy Developer, MicroStrategy Architect and MicroStrategy Intelligence Server.
- Designed Cloud Data Warehouse and ETL pipelines in *Snowflake* along with stored procedures in *JavaScript*, automated data loading with *Python*.

Graduate Research Assistant | Jan 2017 - Aug 2019

<u>University of Nebraska – Lincoln (UNL)</u>

- *Scientific Data Analysis* and data management using *Python* and *R* with packages like *scipy*, *scikit-learn*, *pandas* and *numpy*, utilized parallel computing on Nebraska's second-fastest High-Performance Computing servers.
- Developed a scalable clustering algorithm in *Python* to perform unsupervised learning on GIS data, with performance gain up to 60% compared to state-of-art algorithms. Published and presented research paper.
- Development and management of *PHP* backed application with data visualization using *HTML/CSS*, *KnockoutJS*, *Google Maps JavaScriptAPI* and *MySQL* database. (cse.unl.edu/~surge)
- Developed Agent-based simulation model in *Java* to simulate and predict social unrest on a geographic and temporal scale. (github.com/sudbasnet/SocialUnrestMAS)

Data Software Engineer | July 2012 - Dec 2016

Cotiviti Nepal Pvt. Ltd. | Kathmandu, Nepal | (Subsidiary of COTIVITI HEALTHCARE, Waltham MA)

Software Development - JSP, HTML, CSS | Dec 2015 - Dec 2016

• Software Development using *Java* and *Oracle 11g* on Windows and UNIX platforms. Involved in Integration, Analysis, Design & Development, Testing and Production support phases.

Data Engineer - Oracle 11g/12g | July 2012 - Dec 2016

- Implemented Oracle *PL/SQL* procedures, functions, triggers and packages for data management and statistical report generation. Developed ETL procedures, documented and validated complex rules for data transformation
- Optimized multiple large clients by 60 70% in processing time using parallel processes, re-designing back-end jobs, performance tuning, normalization and query optimization.

EDUCATION

Master of Science, Computer Science (GPA: 3.8) | Jan 2017 - August 2019

University of Nebraska – Lincoln (UNL)

Relevant Courses: Design and Analysis of Algorithms, Data Structures, Machine Learning, Networking, GIS

PERSONAL PROJECTS

- CallBreak An Online Multiplayer Card Game using RESTful API (NodeJS, TypeScript, VueJS, WebSockets): github.com/sudbasnet/Callbreak-Frontend-Vue
- **Personal website** (Angular): https://github.sudbasnet.io